# Rishi Soni

Indore, India <u>rishisoni6071@gmail.com</u>
rishisoni.in +91-9754370193

## **Professional Summary:**

Started as an Intern in Web function, worked as Frontend Intern with Technocolabs, with Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd., and The Spark Foundation. I'm a Regular coder on HackerRank and GeeksForGeeks. And Hands-on Experience on RPA (Robotic Process Automation) as well.

## **Experience:**

Organization : Apisero Global Integrations Private Limited
 Designation : Software Engineer – Aug 2021 to Present

> Organization : Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Designation : Frontend Developer Intern – Aug 2020 to Nov 2020

#### **Technical Skills:**

Languages: Python3, JavaScript, Core Java, SQL, HTML5, CSS3.

- > **Software:** VS Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Automation Anywhere.
- > Other Tools: Git, Github, Bitbucket, Jira, Wix, WordPress.
- Good Understanding of Data Structures, DBMS, OOPS Concepts, Software Development Life Cycle.
- Experience with various JavaScript libraries such as **React.js**, jQuery and CSS frameworks.
- Good working experience with web services integration (REST API, JSON, Ajax, Axios).
- > Hands-on Experience on **Robotic Process Automation** with Automation Anywhere Tool.

#### **Education Qualification:**

- Completed Bachelor of Technology from Shivajirao Kadam Institute of Technology & Management
   Indore with specialization in Computer Science (2018-2022).
- High School and Higher Secondary School Certificate (10+2) from MP State Board.

# **Project Undertaken:**

- ➤ E-Commerce React Application Full E-Commerce App with low-code backend.
- ➤ Weather Forecast Shows real-time data and built with ReactJS.
- ➤ <u>News Website</u> Integrated web services to provide real-time data with pagination.
- ➤ Tic-Tac-Toe Animated & Interactive JavaScript Game.
- > Cover Letter Generation & Instagram Automation with RPA (Robotic Process Automation).

#### **Achievements:**

- ➤ Regular Coder on **GeeksForGeeks** & solved 150+ problems on Data Structures.
- Five Star Rated in Python, SQL, and Java on HackerRank.

## Personal Details:

**Date of Birth** : 06/07/2001 **Languages known** : Hindi, English